Ready, set, go, we step over the goal line
isse nou se de fumikomu gourain
Still, we don't know anything at all
bokura wa nanimo nanimo mada shiranu
We look back as we pass the line, and it's already gone
issen koete furikaeruto mou nai
Still, we don't know anything at all
bokura wa nanimo nanimo mada shiranu
Fiercely, fiercely we move on
udatte udatte udatteku
Drenched in glistening sweat
kirameku ase ga koboreru no sa
There probably were a lot of things we didn't remember
oboetenai koto mo takusan atta darou
Everyone was just a silhouette
daremo kare mo shiruetto
Let's become adults,
daiji ni shitai mono motte otona ni naru nda
holding on to things we want to cherish
And let's keep on protecting them at all times
donna toki mo hanasazu ni mamori tsudzukeyou
Then someday...
soshitara itsu no hi ni ka
We'll be able to laugh at it all
nanimo kamo o waraerusa
Like the light and nimble dancing
hirari to hirari to matteru
Of leaves taking flight
konoha ga tonde yuku
The Imprisoned Pair
(テンテン)ねぇ！ ねえったら！
Hey!
Hey, come on.
あのさぁ 戦ってる場合じゃ
ないと思うんだけど。
Look... I don't think this is
the time to be fighting.
はい。
外に出るまで 一時休戦。
それで いい？
Here.
Let's call a truce
until we get out of here.
What do you say?
(アジサイ)それで いいけど。
大国の施しは受けないわ。
That's fine...
But I don't need charity
from a Great Nation!
施しって何よ？
What? "Charity?"
開封の術。
Unsealing Jutsu!
持ってるなら
そう言えばいいでしょ。
If you had water,
you could have just said so.
大国は 痛みを知らないわ。
The Great Nations...
don't understand pain.
(テンテン)痛み？ 何のこと？
Pain? What are you talking about?
そういうことよ。
Exactly.
自分たちは 痛みも知らず➡
You don't know pain, or the pain
you inflict upon smaller nations.
小国に与える痛みもわからない。
わからないな 何言ってるのか。
I have no idea
what you're talking about.
でも 今は協力が必要ってわかる？
But do you understand
that we need to
ここから出る方法を
一緒に考えよう。
help each other
in order to get out of here?
一緒に？
ここって 何かな？
Help each other?
I wonder where we are.
(アジサイ)風の国の古代遺跡
その地下構造だと思う。
An ancient ruin
of the Land of Wind.
This is probably
some underground structure.
(テンテン)やっぱり？
You think so too?
あそこから 地上に戻るのは
難しそうね。
It looks difficult
to go up that way.
そうね。
I agree.
行ってみる？
それしかないわね。
Shall we try?
We don't have a choice.
(テンテン)ねぇ
あんたの仲間は どう？
How are your teammates?
(アジサイ)どうって？
私の仲間はねぇ➡
What about them?
My teammates aren't suited for
search and rescue...
救助とかサポートとかには
向かないから➡
あんまり 当てにはしてないわ。
So I'm not going to
depend on them to find me...
私も 自力でなんとかする。
I plan to get out of here
on my own as well...
(リー)あっ！
Oh!
(ネジ)何か見つけたのか？
(リー)いえ。
Did you find anything?
遺跡の入り口かと思いましたが
ただの岩でした。
No. I thought this was
the entrance to the ruin,
but it's just a boulder.
雨隠れの里って 一年中
雨が降りっぱなしって本当？
I heard it rains all year long in
Hidden Rain Village, is that true?
そのとおりよ。
ふ～ん。
Yes, it is.
それって 想像つかないな。
I can't even imagine it.
でしょうね。
ん～。
Probably not.
さっきから そういう態度だけど。
You've had an attitude
all this time.
言っとくけど 雨隠れのこと
よく知らないのは➡
But you know, you guys
are also to blame
あんたたちだって悪いのよ。
for us not knowing much
about the Hidden Rain.
私たちが？
(テンテン)うん。
We are?
雨隠れは 秘密主義だと聞くわ。
Yes.
I've heard that secrecy is
a doctrine of the Hidden Rain.
だからね あんたたちのことは
知りようがないでしょ。
So it's no wonder that we don't
know anything about you guys.
唯一の接点は
こうして 中忍試験で会うくらい。
The only time we
come into contact with you guys
is through something like
the Chunin Exams.
しかも 試験だから
話すっていうより戦いだし。
But because this is a test,
instead of talking with each other,
we have to fight.
そうね。
あんたたちは こうして➡
That's true.
You guys can come to
Hidden Leaf Village
木ノ葉や 砂の里に来てるけど➡
or Hidden Sand Village...
私が 雨隠れに行っても
入れてくれないでしょ？
but if we were to go to
the Hidden Rain,
we wouldn't be allowed to enter.
小国の雨隠れには
用心が必要なの。
A small nation like the Hidden Rain
must be extremely careful.
(テンテン)小国は 他にもあるけど
雨隠れは 特別よ。
There are other small nations too...
The Hidden Rain is a special case.
そうね… 雨隠れは特別なのよ。
You're right...
Hidden Rain Village is special.
((小南 : 大国同士の争いに➡
Small nations become embroiled
in the wars of the Great Nations,
小国は常に巻き込まれ➡
戦場となり 痛みを与えられる。
ending up as their battlefields
and are left to suffer
the consequences.
しかしペイン様は こんな世界を
終わりにしようとしている➡
But Lord Pain wants to bring
an end to a world like this...
平和ボケした大国にこそ
痛みを与え➡
He wants the clueless Great Nations
to feel our pain...
真の平和をもたらすおつもりだ。
and bring about true peace.
(小南)
雨隠れは生まれ変わる 新たに))
The Hidden Rain
will be reborn anew...
雨隠れは生まれ変わる。
The Hidden Rain will be reborn.
もう少し友好的になるってこと？
Does that mean
you'll be more friendly?
(アジサイ)それは…。
待って。
– That's...
– Wait.
何か聞こえない？
Did you hear something?
あんたのお仲間？
まさか。
Is it your teammates?
I doubt that...
そうよね。
I guess not.
わっ 何こいつ!?
蟻…。
What is it?!
It's an ant.
(テンテン)こんなにでかいのが!?
An ant this huge?!
あっ かった～い！
It's so hard!
は～っ！
はぁ… さすが魔の砂漠。
They don't call this place
the Demon Desert for nothing...
とんでもない生き物が潜んでるね。
Unreal things live here.
(アジサイ)他にもいるかな？
(テンテン)いてほしくないけど➡
I wonder if there are others?
I hope not...
But these are ants and...
蟻だからきっとワラワラいるかもね。
This place is probably
swarming with them.
捕まえよう。
えっ!?
Let's capture one.
What?
こんなの捕まえてどうするの？
Capture one for what?
口寄せ獣にするため飼い馴らす。
To tame it and turn it into
a Summoning Animal.
口寄せ…。
それに 蟻の巣なら➡
A summoning...
Besides, their nest could be
connected to other openings.
外につながる穴が
あるかもしれない。
うぇ…。
あなた 口寄せできるのよね？
You know how to Summon right?
ええ。
コツってある？
Yes.
Is there a trick to it?
さあ わからないわ。
I wouldn't know.
はぁ やっぱり才能かな。
I guess it's just sheer talent...
うん？
(アジサイ)この奥かしら。
Maybe it's beyond here.
(フヨウ)かすかにチャクラを感じるが…。
I sense a little chakra...
(スイレン)移動しているようだけど
はっきりとはわからないわ。
It seems like she's moving,
but I can't tell for sure.
(コムギ)見つけたぞ！ お前たち！
Found you!
(源内)ここで会ったが100年目。
This is the 100th time we've met!
(イナホ)今度こそ お前たちの巻物を
渡してもらう！
This time, you're gonna
hand over your scroll to us!
(３人)とうっ！
(コムギ)１人いないな。
One of them is missing.
(イナホ)別行動中か？
(源内)となると３対２だ。
Are they operating separately?
Which means it's three against two...
俺たちの優勢だぜ。
and we have the advantage.
なんだ そのボロ傘は？
What's with that beat-up umbrella?
そんなので
何ができるっていうの？
What do you think
you can do with that?
(コムギ)は～っ！
(コムギ)また逃げようってのか？
Planning to run away again?!
今度は逃がさないぜ。
You won't get away this time!
(２人)あっ。
なんだよ お前ら…。
言っておくが➡
Who are you guys?
Let's make this clear.
そいつらは
俺たちの獲物だからな！
Those guys are our prey.
今 この２人を
攻撃するのはやめてもらおう。
You won't be attacking
these two right now.
僕たちは今 協力して
事にあたっているんです。
We're in the midst of
helping each other.
協力？ 雨隠れとかよ。
Helping? The Hidden Rain?
お前ら 同じ木ノ葉のくせに➡
You mean to tell us that
you're Hidden Leaf like us,
逆に俺たちの
邪魔をするってのか？
and you're getting in our way?
同じ受験者だ。
We're all exam participants.
お前たちの巻物を
狙うことだってできるのだが？
If it comes down to it,
we can come after your scroll too.
何だと？
私たちと戦うつもり？
What?!
You want to fight us?
なめんなよ！ だいたい
お前らも２人じゃないか！
Don't underestimate us.
After all,
there's only two of you too.
どうします？ ネジ。
What shall we do, Neji?
(ネジ)無駄な戦闘は避けたいが
しかたがない。
I want to avoid fighting
as much as possible,
but we don't have a choice.
３対２でやるっていうんだな？
So you're gonna come at us,
three against two?
(スイレン)いいえ。
No.
キミたち！
協力しよう。
You guys!
We'll assist you.
(イナホたち)うわっ！
なっなっ なんだよお前ら！
W-What's going on with you guys?
おいっ 本気じゃないよな？
You're kidding, right?
雨隠れと組んで
同じ木ノ葉を襲うなんて。
You're gonna team up
with the Hidden Rain
to fight fellow
Hidden Leaf Shinobi?
(ネジ)二次試験のルールでは➡
According to
the Second Exam's rules,
同じ里かどうかは関係ない。
being from the same village
has no bearing whatsoever.
お前たちが
地の巻物を持っているなら➡
If you possess the Earth scroll,
you're fair game.
単なる獲物だ。
獲物？
ひっ 卑怯だぞ！
Fair game?
Th-That's not fair!
くっ こうなったら…。
If that's the case...
(コムギ)撤退！
(源内)覚えてろよ！
Retreat!
We'll remember this!
(イナホ)絶対 中忍になる！
We're gonna be Chunin,
no matter what!
どうして私たちを助けたの？
Why did you help us?
仲間を助け出すまでは
協力し合ったほうがいい。
To save our teammates,
we need to cooperate.
お前たちも そう思ったのだろう？
Didn't you come to
the same conclusion?
ああ。
Yeah...
では ４人で協力して
テンテンたちを助けましょう。
Then let's all work together
to save Tenten and your friend.
(テンテン)うわぁ。
(アジサイ)巣だわ。
It's the nest...
捕まえるどころじゃないわよ。
There's no way we can capture one...
見て。
ん？
Look.
(アジサイ)蟻の巣穴なら
きっと外に通じている。
The ant hole
must lead to the outside.
(テンテン)だけど ここを突破するの？
And... you're suggesting
we go right through this?
確かに難しそうね。
It looks difficult, doesn't it?
元の通路に戻ったほうがいいよ。
We should go back
to the original corridor.
そうね。
You're right.
(テンテン)やばい！
Not good!
急ごう。
Hurry!
あれが入り口？
間違いなさそうだ。
Is that an entrance?
You're probably right.
よしっ 待っててください テンテン！
お おいっ リー！
Okay! Hang in there, Tenten!
Hey, Lee!
今行きま… おっ。
I'm coming!
おわっ バカでかい蟻がいますよ。
There are ridiculously huge ants!
リー！
Lee!
俺たちをエサだと思っているのか？
We're prey to them.
僕が引き付けます。
I'll distract them.
ネジたちは中へ入って
２人を見つけてください。
Neji, you guys go in
and find the two.
わかった。
Got it!
あっ。
八卦空掌！
8 Trigrams: Air Palm!
急げ！
ええ。
うん。
Hurry!
– Right!
木ノ葉旋風！
Leaf Hurricane!
ここから先は行かせませんよ。
You're not getting past me!
(リー)と言ったところで…。
I guess...
これは通じていませんね。
They wouldn't understand
what I'm saying...
ハァ ハァ ハァ…。
ギギギギ！
(テンテン)なっ 追って来た！
They're chasing us.
ふっ！
ギィ～！
(テンテン)うっ。
ふっ。
えいっ。
はっ。
(２人)あっ。
(テンテン)そんな！
No way...
(スイレン)崩れている。
(フヨウ)通れないのか？
It's caved in...
So we can't pass?
白眼。
Byakugan!
この奥にいる。
ああ。
They're in there.
Yeah, that's Ajisai's chakra.
アジサイのチャクラだ。
Everyone step aside.
みんな離れて。
よせ。
Stop! An explosion
might trigger a cave in.
爆発で落盤の危険がある。
八卦空掌！
8 Trigrams: Open Palm!
(ネジ)パワーを抑えて
一点集中してみたが ダメか。
I suppressed its power
to try to contain it,
but I guess it wasn't effective.
起爆札と変わらんな。
(スイレン)どうする？
Not much different
than a Paper Bomb.
What'll we do?
(フヨウ)おい。
Hey!
チッ。
(テンテン)さっきの振動 何？
What was... that tremor just now?
(２人)あっ。
外からだわ。
It's from the outside.
誰か このがれきを
どかそうとしているのよ。
Someone is trying to
clear this rubble.
あんたのお仲間？
あるいは あなたの。
Your friends?
Or yours.
なんとかしてくれるかな。
難しそうね。
I wonder if they can do it.
Seems it will be difficult.
(２人)あっ。
They're coming!
来た！
待って。
Wait.
口寄せの術。
Summoning Jutsu!
Ward them off.
あいつらを防いで。
(テンテン)どうするの？
What are you going to do?
I'm going to suck the sediment
into another dimension
この土砂を時空間忍術で
別空間に吸い込む。
with my Transportation Jutsu.
(テンテン)どれだけあるかも
わからないのに。
But you don't even know
how much sand and gravel there is!
でも それしかないわ。
This is the only thing left to try.
んっ。
土砂を取り除くか
チャクラが尽きるかよ。
I'll either remove the rubble,
or I'll run out of chakra.
封入の術。
Enclosing Jutsu!
あなたもお願い。
Please, do it too.
Huh?! But I've never
done anything like this...
えっ でも やったことないのに。
武器や道具を
収納するのと一緒よ。
It's similar to stowing away
weapons and tools.
You say it's similar but...
一緒って言われても。
((口寄せの術とは➡
With Summoning Jutsu,
the caster's chakra is
directly proportionate to
術者のチャクラ量に比例して➡
呼び寄せるものの
量や大きさが増えるのだ。
the quantity and size
of what is summoned.
お前は 今 これだけの量の水を
口寄せしたが➡
This is the amount of water
you just summoned.
チャクラ量が増えれば 風呂桶くらい➡
By increasing your chakra,
you can summon enough water
to fill a bathtub, or a lake,
or even an ocean.
湖くらい 大海くらいと
量が増えていくのだ。
大海。
An ocean...
は～！ うわ～。
あっ 来い！
Come here!
うわ～！
(テンテン)無理！
This is impossible!
うまい。
(ガイ)前回の中忍試験のこと
覚えているか？
Do you remember
the last Chunin Exams?
(ネジ)ああ。
(リー)はい。
– Yeah.
– Yes.
うん。
前回は➡
Uh-huh.
The last time,
不測の事態となり
試験そのものは➡
the Chunin Exams were cancelled
due to unforeseen circumstances.
中止の憂き目にあったが。
中忍になれなかったうえに➡
On top of not being
promoted to chunin,
I was useless during
木ノ葉のピンチに
何ひとつお役に立てませんでした。
the Hidden Leaf's
most critical moment.
しかたあるまい。
It couldn't be helped.
お前は ケガがひどく➡
You were seriously wounded
and unable to take action.
活躍するどころでは
なかったからな。
I'm ashamed that I was
perfectly healthy, but helpless.
ピンピンしていたのに面目ありません。
だが 心配はいらぬぞ。
Well, that shouldn't
bother you now.
２年半ぶりに中忍試験が
再開されることになった。
After two years, the Chunin Exams
are being held again.
本当ですか？
Is that true?
And so, I must at least ask you...
そこでまあ 一応 お前たちに
問わなければならない。
３人で中忍試験を受験するか？
Will the three of you take
the Chunin Exams as a team?
当然だ。
やりますとも。
That goes without saying.
Of course we will!
うん。
Uh-huh.
That's the power of youth!
それでこそ青春だ。
We've grown much stronger
since then!
(リー)あのときより
ずっと強くなりました。
(ガイ)どうした？ テンテン
不安でもあるのか？
What's the matter, Tenten?
Are you unsure?
先生 私はあれから
強くなったんでしょうか？
Sensei, have I gotten
stronger since then?
強くなった… はずだ。
You... should have.
目で見える形では
何もありません。
But I have nothing to show for it.
あ…。
ん…。
お前は 間違いなく
あれから努力を重ねてきた。
Without a doubt,
you have persevered
and trained since that time.
確かに ネジやリーのように
目に見える術や技もない。
Admittedly, we can't see it
as we can Neji's jutsu
or Lee's technique.
(ガイ)だがな 忘れるな テンテン。
But do not forget, Tenten.
(努力は 決して
裏切らないということを))
Hard work and effort never betrays.
うぅ… ハァ ハァ。
グァ～！
(２人)あっ！
Unsealing Jutsu!
開封の術！
ハァ ハァ ハァ…。
ちょっと 大丈夫!?
Hey! Are you all right?!
土砂を…。
でも。
– The rubble...
– But...
it's impossible for me to
remove the rubble like you do.
私に あんたみたいなやり方で
土砂を消すのは無理。
Hurry!
早く！ 蟻は穴を掘ってくる！
The ants will dig right through it.
(テンテン)やるしかないっていうのは
わかってる。
I just have to suck it up
and do it!
努力は裏切らないのなら
私のチャクラは増えている。
If hard work and effort
never betrays...
Then my chakra has increased!
は～っ！
"OCEAN"
ハァ ハァ ハァ…。
ん？
うわぁ～！
うぅ…
砂漠で溺れそうになるとは。
I almost drowned in the desert.
ウフ… フフフフ あっ。
You did it.
やったね。
Yeah.
うん。
Seawater in the desert!
砂漠に海水を出すなんて
テンテンの努力の成果が出ましたね。
Tenten, you demonstrated
the fruits of your labor.
(テンテン)でしょ～！ どうよ！
(リー)さすがです！
I sure did, didn't I?!
As expected!
Now then...
さて 俺たちは
一時休戦中だったが➡
We had a truce. So what now?
どうする？
(スイレン)できれば このまま➡
If you agree,
can we continue this truce?
休戦を続けてもらえないかしら？
(ネジ)いいだろう。
It's fine with us.
今さら 戦うって気分にも
なれませんからね。
After what we went through,
I don't feel like fighting.
俺たちは 塔のほうへ
まっすぐ向かう。
We're going to head straight
for the finish line.
我々は… そうだな 右方向を
迂回して 巻物を探そう。
As for us...
Yes...
We'll detour right
and search for a scroll.
Thank you.
(テンテン)ありがとう。
えっ？
Huh?
I got the knack of it,
all thanks to you.
あんたのおかげで
なんとかコツをつかんだみたい。
Yeah? I'm glad.
そう それはよかったわ。
Let's both do our best...
この先 お互い頑張ろうね
三次試験で また会いましょう。
... and meet up in the Third Exam.
Yes.
ええ。
See you again!
またね～！
The other villages
are very curious.
他里は 興味深いな。
Yes... There are so many
different kinds of shinobi.
そうね いろんな忍がいる。
I wonder if Hidden Rain Village
will go through many changes?
(スイレン)雨隠れも
もっといろいろ変わるかしら。
We will change it...
変えるのよ ペイン様と天使様に
お仕えして。
By having faith in Lord Pain
and Lady Angel.
– Yeah.
– Yes.
ええ。
ああ。
Let's go.
行くよ 人柱力を探しましょう。
We have to look for a Jinchuriki.
nando tatakitsukerarete mo
No matter how many times I get beat down
akiramerareru wake nado wanaku genten kaiki
I can't give up, so I go back to my basics
genjitsu to wa baibai shite
I wish we could say bye-bye to this reality
mukashi mitai ni waiwai shitai keredo
And have fun like we used to
sou mo ikanai nara kirihiraite mirya ii
But it doesn't work that way,
so let's carve out our own paths
nokori wazuka no shouki torimodoshite
I'll make you get back the little sanity you have left
me no mae no tobira kojiakete miseru
And then tear down the door in front of you
itsudemo sou nanda
That's the way it is
wasuregachina koto ga
The things you tend to forget
nani yori mo taisetsuna koto datte
Are the things that are the most important
nani ga machiukete iyou to kamawanai
I don't care what lies ahead
ame nimo makezu yami o terasu
The rain won't stop me from lighting up the darkness
kono kyoujin na kokoro ga areba
As long as I have this strong spirit
kono toki kono basho ni tsudoishi nakamatachi
Friends who gather at this time, at this place
mawari tsudzukeru sekai nanbitotari
The world keeps spinning, No one can stop it
tomo tomeru koto wa dekinai yo
We should've just headed
straight for the goal
世界では
存在が明らかになっていない➡
rather than going with
your strategy, Sakura!
未知なる生物の目撃情報が
数多く報告されている。
What?! But you agreed to it!
Ino, you just drank too much water!
そんな
正体不明の生物をとらえた➡
You bloated blister!
Oh yeah, is that right?
衝撃のスクープをご覧いただこう。
Well you'd have to drink
a hundred times more than me!
Next time on Naruto Shippuden:
"The Place Where I Belong"
If we're talking about getting
bloated from drinking water,
then you should have no problem!